我们的扫描结果是对的，舰长
Our scanner survey was correct, captain.
这是高纯度三钛合金
There it is, pure tritanium.
太好了，比金刚石硬20倍
Fantastic. Twenty times as hard as diamond.
- 确切的说是21.4倍 - 谢谢你，史波克
- 21.4 times as hard, to be exact. - Thank you, Mr. Spock.
史考特，对这片岩脉进行标注
Scotty, you can mark this vein as confirmed.
通知星际舰队
Inform Starfleet I recommend
立刻派遣勘探船过来
that they dispatch a survey vessel immediately.
收到，舰长
Acknowledged, captain.
他们很快就会派船舰来勘察
They'll send a vessel fast enough for this rich a find.
我们无法对他进行破坏，舰长
We won't be able to break it, captain.
但我可以用相位器取一块标本
I'll phaser off a specimen.
雷斯利
Lesley.
你闻见了吗？
Do you smell that?
一种发甜的味道，就像蜂蜜
A sweet odour, like honey.
从前我也在一个星球闻见过
It was years ago on another planet.
有一种东西是这个味儿
A thing with an odour like that.
我们现在所在的这个半球
We're in the growing
正是万物生长的季节，舰长
season in this hemisphere of this planet, captain.
这些很有可能是花粉的味道
There are doubtless many pollen aromas.
- 里索 - 是的，长官
- Rizzo. - Yes, sir.
带上你的人，在这四周查看一下
Take your men. Make a swing around our perimeter.
扫描大气中的堤元素成分
Scan for dikironium in the atmosphere.
相位枪设定在裂解档
Set your phasers on disruptor-B.
如果看到任何气状云雾，立刻开枪
If you see any gaseous cloud, fire immediately.
现在是红色警报，去巡逻吧
You're on red alert. Make a sweep.
舰长，准备好传送回来了吗？
Ready to beam back aboard, captain?
还没有，史考特，我们还得在这儿检查一下
Negative, Scotty. We're checking something out.
联邦约克城号准备8小时后和我们会合
The USS Yorktown is expecting to rendezvous with us
我觉得时间有些紧迫了
in less than eight hours, captain. That doesn't give us much time.
收到，待命，寇克
Acknowledged. Continue standing by. Kirk out.
舰长
Captain,
堤元素只存在实验室试验阶段
dikironium exists only in laboratory experiments.
味道没有了
It's gone.
我不可能弄错的
I could've been wrong.
上次我闻到这样的味道
The last time I caught an odour like that...
是在11年前
...was 11 years ago.
之前确实有过堤元素的读数
It seemed to read dikironium for a minute,
但现在没有了
and then I lost it.
好像有什么东西
It's almost like something out there
知道我正在扫描查找一样
knows I'm scanning it.
就好像
And it kind of
为了躲避查找不断变换
keeps changing itself into something different.
这不可能啊，没有物质可以做到这个
That isn't possible. Nothing could do that.
- 舰长！ - 寇克
- Captain! - Kirk here.
舰长
Captain,
有一片奇怪的云雾，长官
there's a strange cloud, sir.
一片，云雾
A cloud... A cloud...
立刻射击
Fire into it immediately!
救命
Help.
史波克
Spock.
死了
Dead.
他们体内已经没有红血球了
And you'll find every red corpuscle gone from their body.
里索还勉强活着
Rizzo's alive. Barely.
寇克呼叫进取号
Kirk to Enterprise.
史考特，锁定我们的位置，急诊待命
Scotty, lock in on us. Medical emergency.
你知道那是什么吗，舰长？
Do you think you know what it was, captain?
那是一种不应该存在的
Something that can't possibly exist.
但又确实存在的东西
But it does.
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇敢的航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：茶包泰迪
校对：喜马拉雅
第二季第十三集
情迷意乱
舰长日志，星历3619.2
Captain's log, stardate 3619.2.
在两名船员离奇死亡后
With the mysterious death of two crewmen,
在该星球上的其余
all personnel
成员迅速撤回到船上
on the planet have been evacuated back to the ship.
- 尸检报告，医生 - 里索少尉怎么样了？
- Autopsy report, doctor. - How's Ensign Rizzo?
- 始终昏迷，长官 - 输血了吗？
- Still unconscious, sir. - Transfusions?
一直在尽最大努力
Continuing as rapidly as possible.
但他的红血球数量还是比正常值低了60%
His blood count is still 60 percent less than normal.
- 寇克呼叫舰桥 - 史波克
- Kirk to Bridge. - Spock here.
已经准备好离开这一轨道了，舰长
Ready to leave orbit, captain.
- 原地待命 - 舰长，请允许我打断一下
- Hold your position. - Cutting in, if I may, captain.
7个小时之后就是
The USS Yorktown is expecting to rendezvous with us
约克城号等待与我们会合的时间了
in less than seven hours.
那你就通知他们，我们晚到一会儿
Then you'll inform them that we might be a little late.
吉姆，约克城号的外科医生
Jim, the Yorktown's ship surgeon
需要知道到底会晚多久到
will wanna know how late.
他准备交给我们的那些疫苗
Those vaccines he's transferring to us
非常容易变质
are highly perishable.
史波克有话说，舰长
Spock again, captain.
西塔VII星现在急需
Those medical supplies are badly
这些药物补给
needed on planet Theta Vll.
他们希望我们能按时把疫苗送到
They are expecting us to get them there on time.
先生们
Gentlemen,
在我弄清楚他们的死因前
we are remaining in
我们将继续停留在这一轨道上
orbit until I find out more about those deaths.
这是我的责任。
On my responsibility. I am perfectly aware
我很清楚给西塔VII星居民所造成的影响，完毕
that it might cost lives on Theta Vll. Kirk out.
- 验尸报告 - 你看见他们的肤色了
- Autopsy report. - You saw their colour.
浑身上下一个红血球都不剩
There wasn't a red corpuscle left in their bodies.
- 伤痕，伤口或者任何形式的切口？ - 什么都发现
- Marks, cuts, incisions of any kind? - Not a one.
从医学的角度上这解释不通
What happened is medically impossible.
我建议你去看看过去那些
I suggest you look at the record tapes
类似的医疗记录
of past similar occurrences.
11年前，联邦法拉古特号的伤亡记录里
You'll find the USS Farragut lists casualties 11 years ago
有着和此次事件惊人的相似
from exactly the same impossible causes.
谢谢，舰长，我会马上查看相关记录的
Thank you, captain. I'll check those tapes immediately.
当务之急
First
你能想办法让里索少尉清醒一小会儿吗？
can you bring Ensign Rizzo to consciousness for a moment?
- 可以，但是 - 这样做会给他造成伤害吗？
- Yes, but it... - Will it hurt him if you do so?
就他现在的情况看
In his present condition,
我觉得没什么区别
I don't think it would make much difference.
那就做吧
Then do so.
输血完毕，长官
Transfusion completed, sir.
他的脉搏和呼吸始终远低于正常值
His pulse and respiration are still far below normal.
给他注射1毫升心索贝，护士
Give him 1 cc of cordrazine, nurse.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
里索
Rizzo.
我是舰长，你能听见我吗？
This is the captain. Can you hear me?
你还记得发生了什么吗？
Do you remember what happened to you?
记，记得？
Remem... Remember?
我好冷
I'm cold.
我觉得好冷啊
I'm so cold.
你被什么袭击了
You were attacked by something.
发生了什么
When that happened, did you notice
你有没有注意到任何气味或者类似的东西？
an odour of any kind?
里索
Rizzo.
里索！
Rizzo!
你记不记得有一股恶甜的气味？你闻到了吗？
Do you remember a sickly sweet odour? Did you smell it?
是的，是的
Yes. Yes.
一种气味，一种奇怪的气味，就好像
A smell, a strange smell. It was like...
就像要被蜂蜜窒息了
Like being smothered in honey.
你有没有感觉到
Did you feel
一种真实存在，那是个有智能的物质？
a presence, an intelligence?
它想从我们身体里面抽取能量
It was trying to draw strength from us.
我能感觉到
I felt it.
它，它
It was... It was...
它在那儿
It was there.
他又陷入昏迷了，吉姆
He's beginning to sleep again, Jim.
我不能冒险再给他打一针了
I can't risk another shot.
他已经告诉我我想知道的信息了
He's already told me what I wanted to know.
鉴于现在他并不完全清醒
I wouldn't depend too much on what
我不会把他的话当真的
he says in that half-conscious state.
他可能说梦话，或是说你想听的那些话
He could be dreaming, saying what he thought he wanted you to hear.
你去看看那些记录带
You check those record tapes.
我需要你尽快给出医学分析
I want your medical analysis as quickly as possible.
舰长这是怎么了？
Well, what's with the captain?
我从没见过他这样
I've never seen him like that before.
我也不知道呢
I intend to find out.
我去医疗记录档案室看看
I'll be in the medical-record library.
舰长
Oh, captain.
星际舰队子空间发来消息，他们要求
Subspace message from Starfleet. They're enquiring...
现在不行，上尉
Not now, lieutenant. Have the security duty officer
让当值的保安队长立刻到剑桥见我
report to me on the Bridge.
- 是的，长官 - 史波克
- Aye, sir. - Spock?
还在持续扫描，舰长
Continuing scanning, captain.
在那个星球表面始终还是没有找到任何生命形式
Still no readings of life forms on the planet surface.
或许我们应该假设
Let's assume
它其实是以一种完全不同的形式存在
that it's something so completely different
传感器没有把它界定为生命形式
that our sensors would not identify it as a life form.
你提到了堤元素，舰长
You mentioned dikironium, captain.
假设它是由非常稀有的元素组成的
Suppose it was composed of that rare element.
一个奇异的，气状生物
A strange, gaseous creature.
我已经扫描过这个元素了，舰长
I have scanned for that element, captain.
星球表面和大气层中
There is no trace
都没有堤元素的迹象
of dikironium on the planet surface or in the atmosphere.
假设它会伪装呢？
Suppose it camouflaged itself.
我们假设它是一个有智慧的生物
Let's assume that it's intelligent,
它知道我们正在找它
that it knows that we're looking for it.
它有意避开传感器的扫描
To hide from a sensor scan,
它可能会改变自身的分子结构
it would have to be able to change its molecular structure.
就像把金子变成了铅
Like gold changing itself to lead,
或是把木头变成了象牙
or wood changing itself to ivory.
你刚提到的现象
You've just suggested something...
我之前居然没想到
...that never occurred to me.
你也许能
It may
从麦考伊医生现在正在查阅的那些医疗记录
provide some answers to a tape record
找到相应的答案
which I think you'll find Dr. McCoy is looking at this very moment.
契科夫，接管扫描仪
Chekov, take over on scanner.
盖洛维克少尉报到，舰长
Ensign Garrovick reporting, sir.
- 你就是新的保安队长？ - 是的，长官
- Are you the new security officer? - Yes, sir.
- 你父亲是？ - 是的，正是家父
- Was your father..? - Yes, sir, he was.
但是我不需要因此而受到任何特殊照顾
But I don't expect any special treatment on that account.
- 在这艘船上没有特殊照顾 - 是的，长官
- You'll get none aboard this ship. - Yes, sir.
舰长，我收到有关里索少尉的消息
Captain, I have a report on Ensign Rizzo.
他去世了，长官
He's dead, sir.
你认识里索？
You knew Rizzo?
是的，长官，我们曾是很好的朋友
Yes, sir. We were good friends.
也是学院的同届毕业生
Graduated the Academy together.
你有机会可以手刃凶手，有兴趣吗？
You'll get a crack at what killed him. Interested?
- 是的，我有兴趣，长官 - 我需要四个人
- Yes, I am, sir. - I want four men
带上相位枪，设定成裂解档
armed with phaser-twos set for disruptor effect.
5分钟后和我在传送室会合
Join me in the Transporter Room in five minutes.
你们跟我一起去那个星球表面
You'll accompany me to the planet's surface.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
读数有变，长官
The reading is changing, sir.
史波克是对的，注意到分子变化了吗？
Spock was right. Notice the molecular shift.
发现堤元素读数了，长官
Dikironium reading now, sir.
方位94，坐标7，仰角6°
Bearing 94, mark 7. Angle of elevation, 6 degrees.
- 保持不动 - 绕过那片高地
- Holding steady. - Over that rise.
带两个人从左边包抄
Take two men, circle around to the left.
我带两个人从右边走
I'll take the other two and go the other way.
那个生物极端危险，如果看到了立刻全力开火
That creature is dangerous. If you see it, fire full phasers.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
贝森，巴多利
Bensen, Bardoli,
跟我来
come with me.
相位枪！快走！
A phaser! Come on!
盖洛维克，你？
Garrovick, did you..?
舰长日志，星历3619.6
Captain's log, stardate 3619.6.
其中一人还在危险期
One of the men in critical condition,
另一个人已经去世，而我
the other is dead. And l...
我现在更加确信
I am now even more convinced
它不仅仅是一个有智慧的生物
that this is not only an intelligent creature,
更是11年前在星系另一端屠杀
but the same which decimated the crew of the USS Farragut
联邦法拉格特号成员的罪魁祸首
11 years ago in another part of the galaxy.
史波克和麦考伊对此却充满怀疑
Both Spock and McCoy are doubtful of this,
我感觉到他们也开始质疑
and I sense they also doubt my decision
我要留下并与它战斗的这个决定了
to stay and fight the thing.
为什么我非要船舰留在这里呢？
Why am I keeping the ship here?
盖洛维克少尉，我们看了你的报告
Ensign Garrovick, we've studied your report.
史波克，你来发问？
Mr. Spock, will you begin?
少尉，你看到的东西有多大？
What was the size of the thing you saw, ensign?
大约10-60立方米，长官
I'd say it measured from 10 to 60 cubic metres, sir.
它的尺寸不定，波动前行
It varied in size, fluctuated as it moved.
- 构成？ - 它好像是
- Composition? - It was like a...
气状的云雾
A gaseous cloud.
其中有一部分很薄，我能看透，另一些部分很厚
Parts of it, I could see through. Other parts were more dense.
少尉，你觉得这一团气状云雾是有智慧存在吗？
Ensign, did you sense any intelligence in this gaseous cloud?
- 我觉得什么，长官？ - 你有没有
- Did I what, sir? - Did you get any
任何潜意识的感觉
subconscious impressions that this
认为它是一个活的有思想的生物体
was a creature, a living, thinking thing,
而不是一团奇异的云状化学元素？
rather than just a strange cloud of chemical elements?
没这个感觉，长官
No, sir.
但是你没有和它有近距离接触，是吧？
But you didn't come into actual contact with it, did you?
没有，长官，我站的离它比较远
No, sir, I was furthest away from it.
好像是平地冒出来的
It seemed to come out of nowhere,
盘旋了一会儿，然后冲向我的人
hovered for a moment, then moved toward my men.
它非常快，快的不可思议
It was fast, incredibly fast.
- 你刚才说它盘旋了一会儿？ - 是的，长官
- Did you say it hovered? - Yes, sir.
你向它开枪了，对吧？
You did fire at it, didn't you?
是的，长官，我开枪了
Yes, sir, I did.
你距离它有多远的距离？
What distance were you from the creature?
大约20码，长官
About 20 yards, sir.
你在这么近的距离
You fired at a large
向一团盘旋的目标射击，居然打偏了？
hovering target at that distance, and missed?
是的
Yes.
它盘旋的时候，我没能及时射击，长官
Well, I didn't fire while it was hovering, sir.
你是说你迟疑了？
You mean you froze?
不是，长官
No. Sir,
- 我没有发愣 - 那你到底干嘛了？
- I didn't exactly freeze. - Well, what exactly were you doing?
我吓了一跳
Well, I was startled for a second,
然后才开的枪，那个东西已经跑了
and then by the time I fired, the thing was already moving.
你还有什么要补充的吗？
Do you have any further information?
- 没有，长官 - 你还有什么问题吗？
- No, sir. - You have any further questions?
我只是犹豫了一下，长官
I only hesitated for a moment, sir.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
少尉，现在解除你的一切职务
Ensign, you're relieved of all duties
回自己的房间禁闭
and confined to quarters
- 等候进一步指令 - 是的，长官
- until further notice. - Yes, sir.
- 你对这个孩子太严厉了 - 他吓傻了
- You were a little hard on the boy. - He froze.
一人死亡一人重伤
One man was killed, another may die.
舰长，从科学的角度上说
Captain, scientifically...
你们俩就此写份报告
You'll both be filing reports.
提出自己的看法和建议
Make your comments and recommendations then.
舰长，在我们待命的这段时间里
Captain, while we wait, I've taken the liberty
我自主清理了2号脉冲引擎的排污口
of cleaning the radioactive disposal vent on Number 2 lmpulse Engine,
半小时后就能完成，我们届时可以出发了
but we'll be ready to leave orbit in half an hour.
我们现在不会离开这个轨道，史考特，暂时不走
We're not leaving orbit, Mr. Scott, not that quickly.
- 舰长 - 在？
- Captain. - Yes?
约克城号询问
Yorktown requesting information on how soon
- 我们还有多久才能与他们会和 - 谢谢
- we expect to rendezvous with them. - Thank you.
这个药不但是西塔VII星现在急需的救命药
The medicine for Theta Vll colony is not only needed desperately,
它的保质期非常短
it has a limited stability...
轮机长，我知道现在面临的情况
I'm aware of the situation, engineer.
并且我很讨厌我船上的高级军官们谋反我
And I'm getting a little tired of my senior officers conspiring against me.
对不起，也许我不应该用“谋反”这个词
Forgive me. Perhaps I shouldn't have used the word "conspired."
同意，长官
Agreed, sir.
扫描仪数据
Scanner readings.
没有发现，长官，还在继续扫描
Nothing, sir. Continuing to scan.
你知道它能自己改变它的分子结构吗？
Are you aware that it can change its molecular structure?
- 知道，长官 - 你有没有
- Yes, sir. - Are you scanning
对任何不正常的活动进行扫描？
for any unusual movement?
- 有的，长官 - 任何形态的气状云雾？
- Yes, sir. - Any type of gaseous cloud?
我们进行了两次全方面扫描
We've run a full scanner probe twice.
那就再扫20遍，直到你找到它
Well, then run it 20 times, if that's what it takes.
希望我没有打扰到你，医生
I hope I'm not disturbing you, doctor.
以任何形式中断尸检都不算是打扰
Interrupting another autopsy report is no disturbance,
史波克，这反而是解脱
Mr. Spock. It's a relief.
我需要你的建议
I need your advice.
那我需要喝一杯庆祝
Then I need a drink.
我不明白这是为什么
I do not understand your reasoning.
你需要我的建议？你开玩笑吗
You need advice from me? You must be kidding.
我不是在开玩笑，医生
I do not joke, doctor.
也许我需要重新组织一下我的用词
Perhaps I should rephrase my statement.
我需要一个观点
I require an opinion.
对于人类的很多不合理的情绪
There are many aspects of human irrationality
我始终还没能完全理解
I do not yet comprehend.
比如，固执
Obsession, for one.
对于一件事执着的固执的态度
The persistent, single-minded fixation on one idea.
- 吉姆和他的神秘生物 - 没错
- Jim and his creature. - Precisely.
你看过发生在联邦法拉格特号上的事故报告吗？
Have you studied the incident involving the USS Farragut?
没有，发生了这么多伤亡事故
No, with all these deaths and injuries,
我只来得及把相关报告扫了一遍
I've only had a chance to scan the tapes.
事故报告记录大约8到10个小时呢
There are eight or ten hours of record tapes there.
幸运的是，我看东西比较快，简言之，医生
Fortunately, I read somewhat faster. In brief, doctor,
这艘舰上的舰长
nearly half the crew
以及近半数船员在那次事故中陨落了
and the captain were annihilated.
舰长的名字叫盖洛维克
The captain's name was Garrovick.
- 和我们的少尉同名 - 那是他的父亲
- The same as our ensign. - His father.
在幸存者中有一个年轻军官
Among the survivors was a young officer
那是他生平第一次执行深空任务
on his first deep-space assignment:
詹姆士·T·寇克
James T. Kirk.
还有一些其他相关信息
And there is still more.
我建议你仔细看看
I suggest you study this.
个人日志，星历3620.7
Personal log, stardate 3620.7.
就为了一个我都无法用语言描述清楚的感觉
Have I the right to jeopardise my crew, my ship,
就把我的船员和船舰至于险地
for a feeling I can't even
这么做对吗？
put into words?
没有人是因为直觉而胜任星际舰队指挥官一职的
No man achieves Starfleet Command without relying on intuition,
但是我的决定合理吗？
but have I made a rational decision?
是不是因为过去的恐惧
Am I letting the horrors of the past
从而影响了我现在的判断力呢？
distort my judgement of the present?
我能进来吗？
Mind if I come in?
寇克呼叫舰桥，数据扫描报告
Kirk to Bridge. Scanner report.
正在持续扫描，长官，没有异常数据
Continuing scanning, sir. No unusual readings.
继续监测，寇克
Maintain search. Kirk out.
它不可能消失的无影无踪
It can't have just vanished.
有时候会的
Sometimes they do, if we're lucky.
怪物们有各种各样的形态
Monsters come in many forms.
你知道最可怕的怪物是什么吗，吉姆？
And you know the greatest monster of them all, Jim?
- 内疚 - 有话直说
- Guilt. - Get to the point.
吉姆，当一个年轻的军官
Jim, when a young officer is exposed
第一次面对未知的险境时
to unknown dangers for the first time,
他同时还承受了巨大的情绪上的压力
he's under tremendous emotional stress.
现在我们都知道
Now, we all know that...
盖洛维克少尉暂时解职是飞船指挥部的裁定
Ensign Garrovick is a ship-command decision.
医生，你越权了
You're straying out of your field, doctor.
是吗？
Am I?
可我刚才谈的是法拉格特号的
I was speaking of Lieutenant James T. Kirk
詹姆士·T·寇克上尉的事儿
of the starship Farragut.
11年前，你还是个年轻的军官
Eleven years ago, you were the young officer
发生袭击时，你在相位室服役
at the phaser station when something attacked.
根据事故报告
According to the tapes,
这个年轻的寇克上尉一直坚持称这是他的过错
this young Lieutenant Kirk insisted upon blaming himself.
因为我没有及时对它开火
Because I delayed in firing at it.
这是你的正常反应，你吓坏了
You had a normal emotion. You were startled.
你一共也就愣了大概2秒钟
You delayed firing for a grand total of perhaps two seconds.
如果我没有延误，它肯定已经被消灭了
If I hadn't delayed, it would have been killed.
船舰的副舰长可不是这么认为的
The ship's exec didn't seem to think so.
对于这个事件他的日志描述的非常清楚：
His log entry was quite clear on the subject:
“寇克上尉是个合格的年轻军官
"Lieutenant Kirk is a fine young officer
在此次事件中表现出了异于常人的勇敢”
who performed with uncommon bravery."
你怎么还不明白？
Don't you understand?
那个东西杀了200个船员
It killed 200 crewmen.
盖洛维克舰长对你来说是很重要的人
Captain Garrovick was very important to you,
是吗，吉姆？
wasn't he, Jim?
是的
Yes.
他是我离开学院后的第一个指挥官
He was my commanding officer from the day I left the Academy.
是我认识的最好的人之一
One of the finest men I ever knew.
如果我当初一看见它就开火
I could've killed that thing
我完全可以把它消灭的
if I had fired soon enough the first time.
你之前并不知道，吉姆，你对此一无所知
You don't know that, Jim. You don't know that any more
也许盖洛维克舰长可以消灭它
than you know that Garrovick could've destroyed it.
我忍不住要这么想
I can't help how I feel. There's
老骨头，那个东西是有智慧的
an intelligence about it, Bones.
是一个邪恶的载体，是个魔鬼
A malevolence. It's evil.
必须要消灭它
It must be destroyed.
别这么执迷不悟了
Don't be so obsessed.
执迷不悟？
Obsessed?
在这么下去你会毁了你自己，毁了你的事业的
That you could destroy yourself, your career.
这只是因为一个年轻人的所作所为
A young boy
让你想起了11年前的自己
who reminds you of yourself 11 years ago.
别毁了我们之间的友谊
Don't push our friendship past the point where I have to take...
我没有，吉姆！
I'm not, Jim!
这是作为医生的专业意见，舰长
This is professional, captain.
我正在准备一份对于星际舰队舰长
I am preparing a medical-log entry on my estimation
身体上以及情绪上的医学评估日志
of the physical and emotional condition of a starship captain.
这份日志会有中校级别的证人在场
Which requires a witness of command grade.
医生，中校，也就是说
Do I take it, doctor, commander,
你们俩或是你们中的一个
that both of you, or either of you,
认为我不称职或是已经丧失指挥能力了？
consider me unfit or incapacitated?
措辞正确，舰长，手册上是这么建议的
Correctly phrased, captain, as recommended in the manual.
我们的回答，就像建议里说的那样：
Our reply, also as recommended, is:
长官，我们注意到最近以来
Sir, we have noted in your recent behaviour
你的一系列行为表现从表面上看不太寻常
certain items which on the surface seem unusual.
我们恭敬地请求您允许我们对此进行进一步的
We respectfully ask permission to enquire further and...
一边儿去，少拿手册说事儿！
Blast it, forget the manual!
有话就问
Ask your questions.
长官，联邦约克城号正在会合地等着我们
Sir, the USS Yorktown is waiting now at the rendezvous point.
船舰上存有易腐坏的药品
It carries perishable drugs...
别跟这儿碎碎念了，这些我都知道
Forget the recitation. I know the facts.
舰长，西塔VII星急需这些疫苗
They need those vaccines on Theta Vll, captain.
那么我们为什么还要在这儿停留？
Now, why are we delaying here?
因为我确定这就是
Because I'm convinced that this is the same creature
11年前攻击法拉格特号的那个生物
that attacked the Farragut 11 years ago.
“生物”，舰长？
"Creature," captain?
我在之前的事故报告里写了
My report is on the tapes.
即使过了11年
As it attacked us 11 years ago, as I
即使我当时失去知觉了
lost consciousness,
我仍然能感觉到那个东西是有智慧存在的
I could feel the intelligence of the thing.
我能感觉到它在思考，甚至谋划
I could sense it thinking, planning.
你说你能感觉到它存在智慧，舰长
You say you could sense
那你是如何感觉到的呢？
its intelligence, captain. How?
它和你有过什么交流吗？
Did it communicate with you?
你声称这是在你失去意识的时候发生的
You state that it happened just as you lost consciousness.
这种半清醒状态的记忆非常不好说
Now, the semiconscious mind is a very tricky thing.
这种状态下一个人很难判断有多少是真的
A man never knows just how much
有多少是想象
is real or how much is imagination.
不管它是什么，医生，随便它是什么
Whatever it is, doctor, whatever it is,
- 你能说它是致命的吗？ - 是的，毫无疑问
- wouldn't you call it deadly? - Yes, there's no doubt about that.
假如它就是11年前
And what if it
发动在据此地超过1000光年的
is the same creature that attacked 11 years ago
星球上的那次袭击同一个生物呢？
from a planet over 1000 light years from here?
显然，舰长
Obviously, captain,
假如它是一个有智慧的生物，假如是同一个生物
if it is an intelligent creature, if it is the same one,
假如它就此推论有在太空中穿行的能力
if it therefore is capable of space travel,
它可能对有生物居住的行星造成重大威胁
it could pose a grave threat to inhabited planets.
有太多的“假如”，我同意
A lot of "ifs," I agree.
但是它们在我下达指令判断时占有相当大的分量
But in my command judgement, they outweigh other factors.
直觉，无关逻辑，史波克
Intuition, however illogical, Mr. Spock,
是一种被认可的指挥特权
is recognised as a command prerogative.
我们不是合伙跟你对着干
We're not trying to gang up on you.
你们确实没有，医生
And you haven't, doctor.
你只是表达了适当的担心，提出了适当的疑问
You've expressed the proper concern, you've asked the proper questions.
你们俩是在履行职责
You've both done your duty.
我能问问你打算怎么写医疗日志吗？
Now, may I ask what medical-log entry you intend to make?
目前来看，我的医疗日志没有相应的结论
At this point, my medical log remains open.
既然这样，先生们
In that case, gentlemen...
- 舰桥呼叫舰长 - 寇克
- Bridge to captain. Come in. - Kirk here.
我这里读到一组数据，舰长
I have a reading on the whatever it is, captain.
它正在离开行星表面，向宇宙出发
Leaving the planet surface, heading into space.
全体船员，红色警戒，红色警戒
All decks, red alert. Red alert.
准备离开这一轨道
Prepare to leave orbit.
舰长，我们不能再继续保持曲速8了
Captain, we can't maintain warp 8 speed much longer.
压力已经接近临界点了
Pressures are approaching the critical point.
范围，契科夫？
Range, Mr. Chekov?
距离0.04光年
0.04 light years ahead.
超出相位炮射击范围，长官
Our phasers won't reach it, sir.
我们几乎很接近它了，舰长
We are barely closing on it, captain.
再有几天就能追上它了
We could be pursuing it for days.
如果有必要
If necessary.
史考特，尽你所能提高我们的速度
Do what you can to increase our speed, Scott.
是，长官
Aye, sir.
放大率开到极限，契科夫
Extreme magnification, Mr. Chekov.
放大率12
Magnification 12.
在那儿，长官，那儿，看到了
There, sir. There, got it.
史波克
Spock,
你那儿的数据怎么样？
how do you read that?
一组相互冲突的数据，舰长
Conflicting data, captain.
它介于物质和能量的临界状态之间
It seems to be in a borderline state between matter and energy,
同时具备两者特征
elements of both.
它应该有能力借助重力场做推进
It could possibly use gravitational fields for propulsion.
这种操作方式简便易行对吗，史波克？
And you don't find that sophisticated, Mr. Spock?
确实非常高效，舰长
Extremely efficient, captain.
但是它是否具有智慧是另一回事儿
Whether that indicates intelligence is another matter.
2号推动引擎舱门呈打开状态
Open hatch on lmpulse Engine Number 2.
史考特正在进行辐射废物清理
Mr. Scott was doing an AID cleanup on it.
我们不会用到脉冲引擎，解除警报
We won't be using the impulse engines. Turn the alarm off.
是，长官
Aye, sir.
舰长，我们不能再追了
Captain, we can't do it.
如果我们继续保持现在这个速度
If we keep this speed,
舰体几分钟后就要爆炸了
we'll blow up any minute now.
降到曲速6
Go to warp 6.
嗨
Hi.
大家都处在警戒状态，我给你带了些晚餐来
Everyone else is at alert stations, so I brought you some dinner.
- 我不饿 - 这是医嘱
- I'm not hungry. - Doctor's orders.
发生什么事了？
What's happening?
我们是不是继续在银河系里
Are we still chasing that thing
追踪那个东西吗？是的
halfway across the galaxy? Yes.
舰长是不是已经不能心平气和了？也许吧
Has the captain lost his sense of balance? Maybe.
全体船员已经准备好迎接大爆炸了吗？当然
Is the entire crew about ready to explode? Positively.
你能置身事外相当幸运了
You're lucky you're out of it.
置身事外是什么意思？
What do you mean, out of it?
这一切都是我的错
I caused it.
你都知道的，是吧？
You know that too, don't you?
如果我在奥古斯X星上没有延误射击时间
If I'd fired my phaser quickly enough on Argus X,
这一切都不用发生了
this wouldn't have happened.
顾影自怜作为头菜来说可不怎么样
Your self-pity is a terrible first course.
要不要来点儿汤换换口味？
Why don't you try the soup instead?
我跟你说了，克里斯汀，我不饿
I told you, Christine, I'm not hungry.
麦考伊医生猜到你会这么说了
Dr. McCoy thought you might say something like that.
这是他给你的正式医疗处方
This is his officially logged prescription for you.
里面只有一个词“吃饭”
It has one word on it: "Eat."
如果你不遵医嘱
Now, if you don't follow his orders,
麦考伊医生可能，而且很有可能会
Dr. McCoy could, and possibly would,
直接把你弄到医务室按倒进行静脉注射
have you hauled down to Sickbay and fed intravenously.
- 这是什么？ - 这个？
- What's that? - This?
天鹅座呼吸疾病调查报告？
"A Survey on Cygnian Respiratory Diseases"?
我以为你去给盖洛维克送吃的了
I thought you took Garrovick some food.
你拿这个干嘛？
What were you doing with this?
进行心理学应用
Applying psychology.
那个生物速度减慢了，降到曲速2
The creature is slowing. It's down to warp 2.
减速
Reduce speed.
慢慢接近
Approach slowly.
我弄不明白了，它明明比我们速度快得多
I don't understand. It was outrunning us.
也许它准备正面应敌了
Maybe it's decided to fight.
- 相位炮就位？ - 相位炮准备就绪，长官
- Phasers ready? - Phasers show ready, sir.
进入战备状态，全体船员进入战备状态
Battle stations. All decks to battle stations.
注意这不是演习
This is not a drill.
全体船员进入战备状态
All decks to battle stations.
呼叫舰桥
Scanner to Bridge.
它暂停了，长官
It's coming to a full halt, sir.
放大1倍
Magnification 1.
慢慢接近，契科夫，1/4光速
Move in closely, Mr. Chekov. Sublight one-quarter speed.
舰长，请求回到我的岗位上
Captain, request permission to return to my post.
进入相位炮射程范围，长官
Within phaser range, sir.
所有相位炮锁定目标
Lock all phasers on target.
- 目标锁定 - 开火，契科夫
- Locked on target. - Fire phasers, Mr. Chekov.
相位炮攻击无效，长官
Phasers ineffectual, sir.
光子鱼雷，密集阵型
Photon torpedoes. Minimum spread pattern.
密集阵型，长官
Minimum pattern ready, sir.
发射光子鱼雷
Fire photon torpedoes.
在那儿，它过来了，长官
There. It's coming, sir.
- 启动偏导仪 - 偏导仪启动，长官
- Deflectors up. - Deflectors up, sir.
- 偏导仪无法阻止它靠近，舰长 - 这不可能！
- The deflectors will not stop it, captain. - That's impossible!
我应该能猜到的
I should have surmised this.
既然它能够借助重力场作为助推力
For the creature to be able to use gravity as a propulsive force,
它应该有能力抵御偏导仪干扰
it would have to have this capacity.
5秒后接触
Five seconds to contact.
所有舱门和通风管道，控制器显示正在全部关闭
All hatches and vents secure. All lights on the board show green.
长官！2号脉冲引擎管道
Sir! The Number 2 lmpulse Vent,
亮着红灯
we have a red light on it.
舰长，有东西从2号推动引擎管道进入
Captain, something's entered through the Number 2 lmpulse Vent.
全舰管道开启负压，全员警戒
Negative pressure in all ship's vents. Alert all decks.
报告
Report.
它从2号推动引擎进来后袭击了两名船员
When it entered lmpulse Engine Number 2's vent,
然后就躲进通风系统管道里了
it attacked two crewmen, then got into the ventilating system,
现在我们剩下的空气只够支持2小时了
and now we have air for only two hours.
- 老骨头 - 其中一个还有存活的可能性
- Bones. - One man has a chance for survival,
另一个已经阵亡了
the other is dead.
这为你此次的魔物追踪又添上了小小的一笔
You can add that little price tag to your monster hunt.
- 够了，老骨头 - 还不够！
- That's enough, Bones. - It's not enough!
只要能为你的业绩增光添彩
You didn't care,
你才不在乎这些代价呢
as long as you could hang your trophy on the wall.
⁮现在好了，不是你追它，舰长，而是它来找你了
Well, it's not on it, captain. It's in it.
先生们，我建议不要在这个话题继续纠缠下去了
Gentlemen, may I suggest we no longer belabour the question
现在争论我们是否应该追踪那个生物
of whether or not we should have gone after the creature.
已经没有任何意义了
The matter has been rendered academic.
这个生物现在正在追击我们
The creature is now after us.
“生物”史波克？
"Creature," Mr. Spock?
它掉头并且发起了攻击，医生
It turned and attacked, doctor.
它的行为模式是经过深思熟虑的
Its method was well-considered and intelligent.
是的
Yes, well,
它完全可以甩下我们好几光年远
it could have been many light years away from us.
而不是掉回头袭击我们，它为什么这么做？
Instead it chose to turn and attack here. Why?
不好说，舰长
Impossible to tell, captain,
除非我近距离调查这个生物
until I can make a closer survey of the creature.
史考特，试试把核废料冲进通风系统管道里
Scotty, try flushing the radioactive waste into the ventilation system.
- 看看有没有什么作用 - 是
- See what effect that has. - Aye.
对不起，吉姆，看来是我错了
I'm sorry, Jim. I was wrong.
舰长
Captain.
这个生物有能力不受时间同步控制
The creature's ability to throw itself out of time sync
这让它可以躲避
makes it possible for it to be elsewhere
相位炮的攻击
in the instant the phaser hits.
所以，你的自我谴责是不成立的
There is, therefore, no basis for your self-recrimination.
即使11年前你开火了
If you had fired on time and on target 11 years ago,
结果和我们一小时前
it would have made no more difference
对它发起的攻击没有什么差别
than it did an hour ago.
盖洛维克舰长还是会牺牲
Captain Garrovick would still be dead.
吉姆，这不是你的错
The fault was not yours, Jim.
事实上，没有人错了
In fact, there was no fault.
史波克，如果你打算进行事件分析
If you wanna play analyst, Spock,
找别人吧，别找我
use someone else, not me.
我担心的是我的船舰和船员们
My concern is with the ship and the crew.
进来
Come in.
少尉，你正在为你之前的失误所困扰
Ensign, am I correct in my assumption that you've been disturbed
我这个假设对吗？
by what you consider to be a failure on your part?
我希望你能考虑到
I would like you to consider
你所自责的那一瞬间的犹豫
that the hesitation for which you are blaming yourself
是因为你的种族天性造成的
is a hereditary trait of your species.
当突然面对未知或极端危险的情况
When suddenly faced by the unknown or imminent danger,
人类总是会表现出一瞬间的瞻前顾后
a human will invariably experience a split second of indecision.
所以才会犹豫
He hesitates.
你在听我说话吗，少尉？
Do I have your attention, ensign?
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
我知道你宁可沉溺在自己的情绪当中
I know you would prefer to wallow in a pool of emotion rather than...
史波克，你过来看我真是太好了
Mr. Spock, it's very kind of you to come here...
仁慈，盖洛维克，这是另一种人类的情绪
Kindness, Mr. Garrovick, is another human emotion.
我认为我们这里的情绪已经够多的了
And I believe we have enough of that.
我只是希望你能够面对现实
I simply would like you to accept the fact
你的反应完全是下意识
that your reaction has its basis in a physio...
你闻见了吗？
Do you smell something?
长官，它从通风道出来了
Sir, it's coming through the vent.
出去！我来关闭通风口
Get out! I'll attempt to seal it off.
长官，那个生物在我屋里，它袭击了史波克
Sir, the creature's in my cabin. It's got Mr. Spock.
马上到，盖洛维克，警戒341室，医疗警报
On my way, Garrovick. Security to 341. Medical alert.
史考特，341室进行反向抽压
Scotty, reverse cabin pressure, 341.
警卫，住手
Security, hold it.
- 三录仪 - 吉姆，史波克有生命危险
- Tricorder. - Jim, Spock may be dying.
如果我们让那个东西进入船舰
If we let that thing
会有更多人跟他一样受到致命威胁
into the ship, he'll have a lot of company.
一定是我刚才扔东西的时候打坏了通风口开关
I must have jammed the vent control when I hit it.
看看反向抽压是不是已经
See if the reverse pressure
把它吸回到通风系统管道里了
has pulled it back into the ventilation system.
他救了我的命，舰长
He saved my life, captain.
我才是应该死在里面的那个人，不是他
I should be lying dead in there, not him.
幸运的是我们俩谁也不用死，少尉
Fortunately, neither of us is dead, ensign.
反向抽压起作用了，通风管道关闭
The reverse pressure worked. The vent is closed.
别误会我这个问题的意思
Don't misunderstand my next question.
史波克，你怎么没死啊？
Mr. Spock, why aren't you dead?
他身上是绿血球
It's that green blood of his.
我的血红蛋白里面是铜元素而不是铁元素
My haemoglobin is based on copper, not iron.
估计那个生物也觉得他尝起来味道不怎么样
I'll bet he left a bad taste in the creature's mouth too.
话糙理不糙
Colloquially expressed, but essentially correct.
是的
Yes.
这次气味不一样
The scent is different.
我觉得我好像明白了
I think I understand something now.
你认为你和那个生物已经可以沟通了吗？
Do you believe you're in communication with the creature?
我不知道那是什么，史波克
I don't know what it is, Mr. Spock.
但你记得我跟你说那东西是有生命的
But you remember I said the thing was alive.
它的沟通方式我们不能理解
It may not be communication as we understand it,
但是我确实知道它是有生命
but I did know it was alive and...
有智慧存在的
...intelligent.
现在我觉得我又发现了一些别的东西
And I think I know something else now.
轮机室呼叫寇克舰长
Engineering to Captain Kirk.
- 寇克 - 史考特，舰长
- Kirk here. - Scott, captain.
那个生物向2号脉冲引擎方向逃离
The creature's moving back toward the Number 2 lmpulse Vent.
使用核废料冲刷管道似乎起作用了
The radioactive flushing may be affecting it.
打开通风管道，我马上去舰桥，寇克
Open the vent. On my way to the Bridge. Kirk out.
- 盖洛维克少尉 - 是的，长官
- Ensign Garrovick. - Yes, sir.
在我们遭受攻击的时候你来过舰桥
You were on the Bridge when we were attacked.
是的，对不起，长官
Yes, I'm sorry, sir.
我知道我应该在舱室关禁闭
I know I was confined to quarters...
勇气可嘉，少尉
Very commendable, ensign.
对于这次反击你有什么看法？
What was your impression of the battle?
我不明白你的意思，长官
I don't understand, sir.
就我们对抗那个生物的手段
I'm asking for your military appraisal.
做一个专业的军事评估
The techniques used against the creature.
无效，舰长
Ineffective, captain.
我知道，舰长，你已经做了各种你能做的措施
I realise, captain, you did everything you could do. I know that.
但在对抗那个怪物时
It's just nothing works against a monster
基本都是无效抵抗
that can do the things that thing does.
少尉，对于你当时
And, ensign,
在星球上的表现你是如何给予评估的呢？
what is your appraisal of your conduct on the planet?
我延误了开火时机
I delayed firing.
如果你没有延误射击时间呢？
And if you hadn't delayed firing?
没有区别的，少尉
No difference, ensign.
已知的武器对于这个怪物而言都是无效攻击
No weapon known would have made any difference.
之前
Then...
或是11年前
...or 11 years ago.
回到你的岗位上，少尉
Report for duty, ensign.
是的，舰长
Yes, captain.
谢谢，长官
Thank you, sir.
- 报告，契科夫 - 好消息，舰长
- Report, Mr. Chekov. - Results positive, captain.
那个生物已经离开船舰并且高速逃离
The creature has left the ship at high warp speed
快要超出我们扫描仪范围了
and is already nearly out of scanner range.
舰长，那个东西移动的方式
The way that thing can move, captain.
- 我觉得难以置信 - 方位，史波克
- I wouldn't believe it. - Direction, Mr. Spock?
之前的方位是127，坐标9
It was bearing 1-2-7, mark 9
现在已经超出扫描范围了
but I have lost it now.
斯考特，我需要在保持船舰不爆炸的前提下
Mr. Scott, I'll need all the speed you can deliver.
速度越快越好，寇克
Keep at it until we begin to shake apart. Kirk out.
我觉得我知道它要去哪儿
I believe I know where it's going.
它可能故意改变航向来误导我们，舰长
It has changed course before to mislead us, captain.
- 从逻辑上讲 - 不，我要跟着感觉走
- Logic would dictate... - No, I'm playing intuition.
契科夫，设定去第谷星系的路线
Mr. Chekov, compute a course for the Tycho star system.
- 设定完成，长官 - 全速前进
- Computed and on the board, sir. - Ahead full.
全速前进，长官
Ahead full, sir.
乌呼拉上尉
Lieutenant Uhura
与星际舰队和联邦约克城号建立联系
contact Starfleet and the USS Yorktown.
联系通道畅通，长官
Frequency open and clear, sir.
通知他们我们正在追踪
them that we are pursuing the creature
该星系IV星的那个生物
to Planet IV of that system.
那正是它11年前袭击联邦法拉格特号的地方
That's the location of its attack on the USS Farragut 11 years ago.
我不明白，舰长
I do not understand, captain.
在盖洛维克的舱室
In Garrovick's quarters,
我当时说那个生物的气味不一样了
I said the scent of the creature was different.
那是一种在我头脑里类似于“家”的感觉
Something in my mind said "home."
那你知道它的家是哪儿，舰长？
And do you know where home is, captain?
是的，我应该知道
Yes, I think I do.
我不知道我是怎么知道的，但是
I don't know how I know, but home...
家，就是它最早遇到星舰的地方
...is where it fought a starship once before.
告诉他们我们的战术态势
Give them our tactical situation.
我们将全力追捕
Inform them I'm committing this vesse
灭杀那个生物
to the destruction of the creature.
这之后我们会返航与他们会和
We will rendezvous...
具体时间，契科夫？
Roundtrip time, Mr. Chekov?
1.7天，长官
1.7 days, sir.
我们会在48小时后
We will rendezvous with the USS Yorktown
与联邦约克城号会和
in 48 hours.
我觉得你现在已经确信
I assume you now believe
我们能追上这个生物并且消灭它
we should pursue the creature and destroy it.
- 的确 - 你不同意史波克的意见？
- Precisely. - You don't agree with Mr. Spock?
时间对我来说才是最头疼的事儿
It's the time factor that bothers me.
那些药品非常容易变质
Those drugs are perishable.
医生，证据显示那个生物正准备产下后代
Doctor, evidence indicates the creature is here to spawn.
若果真是这样
If so
它是通过裂变进行繁衍
it will reproduce by fission,
那就不会是仅仅两只了
not just into two parts,
会裂变成成千上万
but thousands.
反物质是我们唯一的希望
Antimatter seems our only possibility.
一盎司就足够了
An ounce should be sufficient.
我们可以从船舰轮机上抽取
We can drain it from the ship's engines,
然后放置在一个真空磁场容器里
transport it to the planet's surface
把容器安放在星球上
in a magnetic vacuum field.
通知医务室，我需要尽可能多的血浆
Contact medical stores. I want as much hemoplasm as they can spare
15分钟后送到传送室
in the Transporter Room in 15 minutes.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
我猜你打算用血浆作为诱饵然后发动袭击
I presume you intend to use the hemoplasm to attract the creature.
我们需要把它弄到反物质那儿去
We must get it to the antimatter.
既然红血球能吸引它
It seems attracted to red blood cells.
用作诱饵再合适不过了
What better bait could we have?
还有一个问题，舰长
There is still one problem, captain.
- 爆炸，是的 - 没错
- The blast, yes. - Exactly.
物质反物质爆炸会把星球上的
A matter-antimatter blast
半个大气层都掀掉的
will rip away half the planet's atmosphere.
如果我们的船舰在此轨道上停留
If our vessel
而后收到冲击波的影响
is in orbit and encounters those shock waves...
我们必须抓住这个机会，史波克
A chance we'll have to take, Mr. Spock.
我们不能确保在这样的恶劣条件下
We cannot be certain the transporter
传送站还能继续工作
will operate under those conditions.
如果在把人传送回来的时候正好遇到冲击波
If a man is beaming up when that hits,
那很有可能造成传送失败
we may lose him.
这就是为什么我打算亲自去布置这个陷阱
That's exactly why I've decided to set the trap myself.
舰长
Captain,
我的绿色血液中只有少量血红蛋白
there is so little haemoglobin in my green blood,
那个生物没有办法对我造成实质伤害
the creature could not harm me extensively.
那么从逻辑上看来，我应该是最适合的人选
It therefore seems logical for me to be the one...
否决，史波克
Negative, Mr. Spock.
假如计划失败，我需要你在船上控制局面
In case this plan fails, I'll need you aboard the ship.
那样的话，我们需要其他的解决方案
In that event, we'll need another plan.
需要两个人把反物质装置传送下去
It will require two men to transport the antimatter unit.
我请求和你一起执行此次任务，长官
I'd like permission to go with you, sir.
我也正有此意，盖洛维克
I had you in mind, Mr. Garrovick.
- 寇克呼叫进取号 - 史波克在，舰长
- Kirk to Enterprise. - Spock here, captain.
立刻前往传送范围内距离最远的轨道
Proceed immediately to maximum orbit.
收到
Acknowledged.
刚刚忽然想到，舰长，不到1盎司的反物质
Just think, captain, less than one ounce of antimatter here
威力比1万颗钴弹还要厉害
is more powerful than 10,000 cobalt bombs.
我们只能希望它对付那个生物
Let's hope it's as powerful
就像它对付人一样
as man will ever get.
- 导火索 - 是，长官
- Detonator. - Aye, sir.
寇克呼叫进取号
Kirk to Enterprise.
史波克在，舰长，停留在据此3万公里的轨道了
Spock here, captain. Holding at 30,000 kilometres.
反物质容器已经安放到位并开启
Antimatter container positioned and armed.
它一上钩我就叫你，寇克
I'll call you back when it's baited. Kirk out.
舰长，快看！
Captain, look!
血红素，它把诱饵都吃光了
The hemoplasm. The bait's already taken.
我们得再找点儿什么东西做诱饵
We'll have to use something else for bait.
长官，那个东西只对血液感兴趣
Sir, that thing only feeds on blood.
盖洛维克，回到船上
Garrovick, get back to the ship.
告诉他们准备爆破
Tell them to prepare to detonate.
舰长，你不能拿自己当诱饵
Captain, you're not gonna be the bait.
我已经说了，回船上去
I said, get back to the ship.
- 少尉，这是命令 - 是，长官
- Ensign, I gave you an order. - Yes, sir.
别在这儿想当然了，没时间逞英雄
Consider yourself on report. This is no time for heroics.
我可没打算自我牺牲
I have no intention of sacrificing myself.
至少现在没这个打算
At least, not yet.
史波克？史波克？
Spock? Spock?
史波克在
Spock here.
扫描我们
Scan us
锁定我们的位置，那个东西正在向我们靠近
and lock onto us. It's going to be close.
非常非常近了，准备
Very, very close. Stand by.
进取号，准备
Stand by, Enterprise.
我已经可以闻到它了，舰长
I can smell it, captain.
那种让人恶心的
It's sickly.
甜得发腻的味道
Honey-sweet.
进取号，准备
Stand by, Enterprise.
现在！激活并引爆！
Now! Energize and detonate!
重置
Reset.
激活
Energize.
全体船员，准备，冲击波来了！
All decks, stand by. Shock waves!
- 想想办法 - 我们正在做，医生
- Do something. - We are, doctor.
交叉回路到A
Cross-circuiting to A.
接收到了，好歹收到一部分影像了
Got them. A piece of them, anyway.
交叉回路到B
Cross-circuiting to B.
这种传送方式简直是疯了
Crazy way to travel.
把人打撒成分子结构分散到整个宇宙里
Spreading a man's molecules all over the universe.
舰长，谢天谢地
Captain. Thank heaven.
斯考特，这与神灵没有什么关系
Mr. Scott, there was no deity involved.
是我转换交叉点路到B段才把他们复原的
It was my cross-circuiting to B that recovered them.
那么，就谢谢干草叉和尖耳朵
Well, then, thank pitchforks and pointed ears.
只要人能回来，谢谁都行，吉姆
As long as it worked, Jim.
说的不错，老骨头
That's a fair statement, Bones.
现在那个生物已经灭杀了
Now that the creature is dead,
让我们去拯救其他人吧
let's save some lives.
我们去递送你的那些药品
We'll deliver your medicine.
- 舰桥，寇克呼叫 - 乌呼拉
- Bridge, this is Kirk. - Uhura here.
让契科夫设定好路线与约克城会和
Have Mr. Chekov lay a course for rendezvous with the Yorktown.
- 全速前进 - 是的，长官
- Maximum warp. - Aye, sir.
少尉，你整理好后去我的舱室找我
Oh, ensign. Meet me in my quarters when you've cleaned up.
我想跟你聊聊你父亲
I'd like to talk to you about your father.
很多
Several...
奇妙的经历，我觉得你会感兴趣的
...tall stories I think you'd like to hear.
谢谢，长官
Thank you, sir.
我肯定会
I would.
TLF字幕组欢迎你，欢迎有志之士加入
TLF微博http://weibo.com/tlfsubs/
TLF中文字幕站http://subs.eastgame.org/